<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Neuro Madness</title>
    <description>What is going on?</description>
    <link>https://neuromadnessorg.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://neuromadnessorg.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 01:17:50 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 01:17:50 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>No, Coconut Oil is not bad for you.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, mainstream media outlets have been bombing the internet quite a lot with many articles blaming Coconut Oil for many of your health problems.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
With devastating headlines such as “Coconut oil isn’t healthy. It’s never been healthy”, it’s quite clear that what we are seeing here is industry funded premium articles&lt;br /&gt;
 promoting the &lt;strong&gt;already debunked&lt;sup&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; idea that Saturated Fats are harmful for the health, shifting the focus from added sugars.&lt;br /&gt;
 [Virgin] Coconut Oil has been shown to have antimicrobial activity&lt;sup&gt;[2]&lt;/sup&gt;, to be a great antioxidant&lt;sup&gt;[3]&lt;/sup&gt;, and even there is anecdotal evidence that it has been useful both topically and ingested for horrible diseases such as ALS&lt;sup&gt;[4][5][6]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great take on the issue, by the wery well respected Neurologist Dr. Perlmutter can be found in here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.drperlmutter.com/is-coconut-oil-still-healthy-the-truth-behind-the-recent-headlines/&quot;&gt;Is Coconut Oil still healthy?, the trust behind the recent headlines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[1]: https://www.ucsf.edu/news/2016/09/404081/sugar-papers-reveal-industry-role-shifting-national-heart-disease-focus&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[2]: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24328700&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[3]: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/28412883&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[4]: http://www.drperlmutter.com/use-ketogenic-diet-treating-als/&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[5]: https://www.researchgate.net/publication/271909520_ALS_untangled_15_Coconut_oil&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[6]: http://coconutketones.blogspot.com/2012/05/als-patient-two-year-update-on-coconut.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://neuromadnessorg.github.io/general%20health/2017/07/07/No-coconut-oil-is-not-bad-for-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://neuromadnessorg.github.io/general%20health/2017/07/07/No-coconut-oil-is-not-bad-for-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>site</category>
        
        
        <category>General Health</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The best natural treatment for Lyme disease</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Lyme Disease affects millions every day, it’s a poorly understood debilitating illness &lt;strong&gt;caused by a bacterium called Borrelia Burgdorferi sensu lato&lt;/strong&gt;. It can mimic or cause all sorts of more commonly known syndromes, such as Multiple Sclerosis&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#cite-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, ALS&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#cite-2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#cite-3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, Rheumatoid Arthritis&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#cite-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, or Alzheimer&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#cite-5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. It’s a very complex illness, and if it wasn’t enough, it usually presents itself with a host of other infectious agents, such as Bartonella sp, Babesia sp, Mycoplasma sp, Chlamydia and others, making the clinical picture in most cases very insidious, unspecific and thus difficult to diagnose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As one of the first doctors that started treating this disease, who eventually had to abandon practice, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lymenet.org/BurrGuide200810.pdf&quot;&gt;open sourcing his work&lt;/a&gt; puts it in front of the Senate in 1993, some have called this &lt;strong&gt;The Lyme Disease Conspiracy&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LjvTonxC__8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You read it right, 1993, 24 years ago, and I would say that things might be worse now in some respects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As world renowned Lyme expert Joseph Jemsek puts it, “Lyme disease is the next tsunami”, and indeed it is: The internet is furious, full of people tired of being let down by their medical establishment, and looking for answers. You might not have that Doctor at hand who will be willing to prescribe long term antibiotics, or simply cannot afford it. Thankfuly, there are other options, remember this, there is always hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter Stephen Buhner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen Buhner is an american herbalist, poet, and author, descendant of Leroy Burney, the eight Surgeon General  of the United States under Kennedy and Eisenhower, he is an extremely intelligent individual who has dedicated a couple of decades to research this disease, and has been perfecting a protocol with the help of the thousands of patients that over the years have given feedback. He is a world expert in Herbal Medicine, and his digestion of existing scientific research is incredible. His books are full of scientific references, and his gift as a writer makes reading his books a delightful experience. I recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-is-this-buhner-protocol-all-about&quot;&gt;So what is this Buhner Protocol all about&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key aspect of the &lt;strong&gt;Buhner Protocol&lt;/strong&gt; for Lyme disease and coinfecions, is that it’s not fixed, it’s not a set of pills or herbs thing, he seems to have fully understand the basis of the problem, and in contrast with a lot of other conventional Lyme doctors, he considers major symptoms that make Lyme patients’ life miserable a priority to solve, so that patients can become more active, healthier and stick better with the rest of the protocol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The protocol that Stephen Buhner recommends for treating Lyme Disease consists of a “core”, which is going to be the same, or really similar for everyone, and then differerent additions depending on different coinfections or differences in symptomatology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-core-protocol&quot;&gt;The core protocol&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;endothelial-protection-japanese-knotweed&quot;&gt;Endothelial Protection (Japanese Knotweed)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According Buhner himself, the herb &lt;strong&gt;that is having more success&lt;/strong&gt; in tackling a Borrelia infection longterm is &lt;strong&gt;Japanese Knotweed&lt;/strong&gt;. This plant, with latin name &lt;strong&gt;Polygonum Cuspidatum&lt;/strong&gt; widely used in Chinese medicine, mainly for circulatory issues, by the name Huzhang (虎杖), according to Stephen Buhner, &lt;em&gt;seems&lt;/em&gt; to be the most specific tackling the cytokine cascade that these Borrelia bacteria initiate. In his own words:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“After a decade of experience with it, it’s pretty reliable in &lt;strong&gt;reversing symptoms&lt;/strong&gt; [of Lyme Disease] for most people who use it”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of it’s main active compounds is &lt;strong&gt;Resveratrol&lt;/strong&gt;, which might be familiar for the readers, and it’s been researched all accross the globe with promising results for a variety of conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This plant appears to protect endothelial cells from damage caused by these intraceullular infections, preventing the pathogens from causing further damage, as well as functioning as a synergist, enhancing the action of other herbs or antibiotics that may be taken at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dosage Buhner recommends is as follows&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#cite-4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Powder:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 teaspoon to 1 table spoon of the root powder 3x daily. Start at 1 teaspoon and work up slowly.&lt;br /&gt;
(This is the form that was of most benefit to me) or…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tincture:&lt;/strong&gt; 1/4 to 1 tsp 3-6x daily, or…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tablets&lt;/strong&gt;: These are the ones you find in your regular store labeled &lt;strong&gt;Resveratrol&lt;/strong&gt;, but make sure that it comes from Polygonum Cuspidatum and not from grapes. The dosage that Buhner recommends is the same listed usually in the bottles (2 tables per day, with 500mg per table, giving 80mg total reserveratrol a day with 20mg of resveratrol itself.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cytokine-remodulation&quot;&gt;Cytokine remodulation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another strategy of his protocol is to modulate the pro-inflammatory Cytokine cascade [an entire article about this is underway] that these bacteria initiate leading to all sorts of chronic health problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His battle tested approach for this are the &lt;em&gt;Combined tinctures&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Salvia Miltiorrhiza&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Scutellaria Baicalensis&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dosage as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tincture&lt;/strong&gt;: 1 tsp 3x daily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;collagen-protection&quot;&gt;Collagen protection&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also a big one. This was of great benefit for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Great lakes gelatin powder. 1 tbl, once a day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vitamin C: 1000 - 3000mg daily (Some might have kidney concerns but at that dosage it appears to be fine)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Selenium: 200mcg daily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;immune-remodulation&quot;&gt;Immune remodulation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uncaria tomentosa bark
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Powder: 1 tsp 3x daily, or…&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Tincture: 1/4 to 1/2 tsp 3x daily, or…&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Tablets / capsules: 1-4 500mg tablets/capsules 3x day&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cordyceps mycelium
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Powder: 1tsp-1tbl 3x daily, or…&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Tincture: 1/2-1 tsp 3x daily&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Withania somnifera
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Powder: 1/2 tsp in a.m., 1 tsp p.m. before bed.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eleutherococcus senticosus
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Tincture: 1/2 tsp 3x daily.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glycyrrhiza
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Tincture: 1/4 tsp 3x daily.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;antispirochetal&quot;&gt;Antispirochetal&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Warning: This herb might be too hard on people with an ALS type lyme, where too much herxing is often detrimental, causing more neuronal death. So caution is advised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andrographis capsules: &lt;em&gt;Begin with a dose and work up&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;neuroborreliosis&quot;&gt;Neuroborreliosis&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very important herb in his protocol is &lt;strong&gt;Uncaria rhyncophylla&lt;/strong&gt;, the dosage he recommends is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tincture: 1/2 - 1 tsp 3-6x daily, depending on the severity of brain infection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-expanded-protocol&quot;&gt;The expanded protocol&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the core protocol seems to be very useful by itself, having us seen it first hand, this author’s research has also focused in address specific reported symptomatologies, so that patients quality of life can improve more rapidly while on it, and to account for differences in clinical presentations, which, in Lyme disease complex, are many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[To be continued]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;cite-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=QCeWncdRhQQC&quot;&gt;Why Can’t I Get Better? Solving the Mystery of Lyme and Chronic Disease&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;cite-2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;: Motor neuron disease recovery associated with IV ceftriaxone and anti-Babesia therapy. DOI: 10.1111/j.1600-0404.2006.00727.x&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;cite-3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;: Generalised motor neuron disease as an unusual manifestation of Borrelia burgdorferi infection. DOI: 10.1136/jnnp.63.2.257&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;cite-4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;: Healing Lyme. Natural Healing of Lyme Borreliosis and the Coinfection Chlamydia and Spotted Fever Rickettsioses. Stephen Harrod Buhner&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;cite-5&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;: Cystic borrelia in Alzheimer’s disease and in non-dementia neuroborreliosis. DOI: 10.1016/j.jalz.2006.05.1465&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://neuromadnessorg.github.io/lyme%20disease/2017/05/05/The-best-natural-treatment-for-lyme-disease.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://neuromadnessorg.github.io/lyme%20disease/2017/05/05/The-best-natural-treatment-for-lyme-disease.html</guid>
        
        <category>site</category>
        
        
        <category>Lyme disease</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
